

TRẦN THỊ VIỆT NGA

Email: vietnga2905@gmail.com Phone: +84 368 324 99

With 5 years of experience in the e-commerce industry, I have developed strong skills in problem-solving and data analysis. I thrive in progressive environments, always seeking new challenges and opportunities for growth. I want to find a company where I can create practical values and commit long-term

EXPERIENCE

METRIC _ Business Development (B2B Clients)

9/2024 - Present

1. Customer Relationship Management:

- Build and maintain long-term relationships with customers.
- Provide solutions and services tailored to each customer to reach agreements on contracts.
- Advise on product packages, close deals, provide customer care and follow-ups, upsell, and renew contracts.

2. Contract Monitoring and Performance Evaluation:

- Monitor the progress of contract implementation and ensure that goals are achieved.
- Evaluate the effectiveness of the contract and suggest improvements.

Assistant Homestay Manager (Freelance)

11/2023 - Present

- Collect and analyze guest feedback to identify areas for improvement and implement necessary changes.
- Assist in budgeting, invoicing record-keeping for homestay operations.

LAZADA_ Senior Key account management (FMCG- Homecare)

02/2023 - 12/2023

1 Category tracking performance

- Analyze and research market trends, competitor activity leading to strategic pricing adjustments that increase sales
- Collect data and Create valuable performance reports weekly/monthly/quarterly to the line manager using Power BI and Excel
- Track, Monitor, and forecast performance daily/ weekly/ monthly
- Identify the problem of Category and find the practical solution to improve sales

2 Key Account management (Managed ~ 25 to 35 seller)

- Work closely with sellers to support their performance by providing data-driven insights and recommendations.
- Maintain constant stock availability by analyzing inventory data and managing reorder points.

SHOPEE_ Senior Business Development (FMCG - Grocery & Homecare)

12/2021 - 06/2022

1 Category Campaign management

- Analyse Data to identify customer behavior patterns, and market trends to support Merchandise team decision-making.
- Collaborate closely with the Merchandise team on projects to improve effectiveness for tracking and optimizing campaigns
- Forecast based on the latest historical data for Campaign
- Report the results of the Campaign to line manager

2 Key Account Management

- Provide strategic advice to seller on how to maximize their sales performance
- Analyze performance and market insights from seller's perspectives
- Coach sellers on competitive pricing and store operations Suggest promotions, sell marketing services

3 Make internal report for team member

- Allocate targets, performance for subcategories & team members
- Build analytics dashboards to get insights and track team performance weekly/ monthly

Key Achievement: Plan & Execution Successful Grocery week TET 2022 (8 days): Uplift 1,5X vs normal day

SHOPEE, Associate Business Development (FMCG - Grocery)

12/2018 - 12/2021

1 Flash Sale & Deal Hunting Project Collaborator

- Responsible for the entire operation of the Category Flash sale, Deal hunting
- Set deadlines, prioritize tasks, and assign team members to multiple deliverables
- Forecast, allocate rebate budget, warrant performance of project on track

2 Seller incubation: (including 3 months internship)

- Provide strategic advice to merchants on how to maximize their sales performance
- Pitch sellers to join suitable packaged solutions to grow their business
- Coordinate with other departments to promptly solve arising problems for sellers.

Key Achievement: 3 consecutive quarters ranked at the top 1 of Grocery Category performance rankings

SKILLS

- **Data Driven**: Excellent at combining data analysis and business sense to provide practical insight. BANK

- Computer: Power BI (PL-300 certification), MySQL and Proficient in MS PowerPoint, Microsoft Excel
- **Negotiation skills**: Experienced and strategic approach when dealing with customers.

EDUCATION

BANKING ACADEMY (2015- 2020) Management Information System Major